Changiz Rezvani (B.Sc., M.Sc.)

Software Developer/Web Designer / Freelance Developer

Mobile: 07541 308886 | Email: changiz.rezvani@gmail.com | Address: SE18

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/changiz-rezvani/

Website: http://www.changiz2014.biz/More

SUMMARY

I am a versatile and self-motivated, Information Technology professional with over 19 years of top-notch experience in quality software development, object-oriented programming, overall system design, database implementation and web design. My core competencies include code development, object-oriented design, website design & development, and project management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software development: Visual Studio 2017, .Net Framework 4.5, VB.NET, C#, ASP.NET, DevExpress 18.1.6, ReSharper, Productivity Power Tools, Code Debugging, Code Refactoring

VB 6.0, VB Controls, ActiveX COM & DLL, Windows API, DAO 3.6, MZ-Tools

Web Design: Iron Speed CMS, T-SQL, HTML 5, CSS 3.0 and JavaScript 2.0

Windows: Windows 10/MS Office 2016/Outlook 2016/Adobe Acrobat/Corel's

Photo & Video Studios/Microsoft Edge

Project Management: Team viewer

KEY SKILLS

- Demonstrated a strong ability to analyse & solve problems
- Track record of successfully handling multiple projects all at the same time
- Proven track record of developing creative strategies
- Excellent knowledge of programming and IT both general and in detail
- Able to work effectively with superiors, peers, and subordinates
- Project a self-confident, authoritative but friendly and enthusiastic personality
- Extremely versatile in providing help and support for others in their work
- Track record of developing positive working relationships
- Make a favourable impression and easily gains acceptance of others
- Able to fairly and effectively work as part of a team
- For the past 5 years, continually updating & upgrading my marketable skills with Lynda.com my favourite training website – absolutely fabulous

ACADEMIC EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

M.Sc. in Computer Machine Intelligence	UNIVERSITY OF SURREY	1993
M.Sc. in Digital Electronics & Computing	UNIVERSITY OF KENT	1987
B.Sc. in Computer System Engineering	UNIVERSITY OF KENT	1979
A-Levels Math (Pure & Applied) & Physics	LONDON F.E. COLLEGE	1976

SELECTED ACHIEVEMENTS

- Continued with upgrading of <u>Plant Simulation and Modelling</u> software in .Net for APM Global, Jul 2019 - Now (As business partner until the court case against MES is settled)
- Continued with upgrading of <u>Plant Simulation and Modelling</u> software in .Net for MES,
 Jan 2019 Apr 2019 (self-employed)
- Continued with upgrading of <u>Plant Simulation and Modelling</u> software in .Net for MES,
 July 2018 December 2018 (fixed term contract)
- Travelled abroad on business, as well as worked as freelancer on various Web and Software projects May 2017 – Sep 2018
- Designed and extensively upgraded <u>Plant Simulation and Modelling</u> software in .Net for MES, 2014 – 2017
- Created an <u>Online Job Tracking and Asset Management</u> software for MES, 2014
 2015 Login using id: changiz2008@gmail.com & pwd: plasma123456
- Re-coded and extended Safety and Risk Analysis software for MES, 2012 2013
- Designed an <u>Online Trading Website</u> for the Precious Metal Trading Company, GMPT,
 2009 2012
- Coded <u>Plant Simulation and Modelling</u> software for Sim. Eng. initially in VB6 and then VB.Net, 2000 –2008
- IT Lecturer in C, C++, OOPS at various London academic Institutions 1995-1999
- Lecturer of Computer Science, European University of Cyprus, 1994 1995
- Intelligent Computing Research Associate UNIVERSITY OF SHEFFIELD 1991
- Intelligent Computing Research Assistant UNIVERSITY OF WALES 1990

RECENT TRAINING:

Digital Marketing and SEO Optimisation with Newskills Academy 2019

Advanced C#/.Net Programming/Responsive Web Design/Project Management & 2018

Other IT related topics at LinkedIn Learning aka Lynda.com

HTML 5.0 | CSS 3.0 | JavaScript | ASP.Net | A+ certifications & Other IT related stuff at Career Match UK 2017

Business, Technology, <u>IT Skills certifications</u> & Various other IT & business related courses at Lynda.com

2014-2017

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Partnership (until the court settlement against MES is decided) Continued

Jul. 2019 – Sep. 2019

working on Plasma+ for APM Global, and became a partner in the business.

Self-Employment Work

Jan. 2019 – Apr 2019

Continued working on Plasma+ on a self-employed basis.

Fixed Term Contract Work with MES International

Oct. 2018 – Dec 2018

Secured a contract for the re-designing of MES in-house software now called PLASMA

+ from ground up for creating a cloud-based version of the software

Freelance IT Consultancy Work/Personal Development 2018

Sep. 2017 – Sep

I was trying to secure a contract by submitting a proposal for the re-designing of MES inhouse software PLASMA from ground up for creating a cloud-based version of the software.

Website Design & IT Workarounds & e-Trade – Adding new features and pages to clients' websites, working on opening Amazon e-shop with partners to sell products from Iran.

Freelance IT Consultancy Work/Personal Development Sep. 2017

May 2017 -

Made use of the gap in the employment and travelled abroad for business purposes.

Software Developer / Web Designer MES INTERNATIONAL Ltd Sep. 2012 – Apr. 2017

Innovative and multidisciplinary consulting company providing services in the Energy, Chemical and Process industries

- Built an <u>Employees Tracker</u> Project a software package that helps employees submitting their time sheets online and the managers to budget the company expenses accordingly ASP.Net/SQL/JS/HTML/CSS/ISD CMS
- Plasma Project A commercial desktop engineering application extensively used by BP and other similar oil and gas companies for plant simulation, coded in VB.Net/C#/VB6
- Supervised the junior programmer(s) in order to upgrade the Plasma software to .Net –
 VB.Net/C#
- AMNIS project a software developed specifically for the oil and gas industry with the purpose of assessing the safety of the plants. The project involved upgrading and improving the existing code VB.Net
- Preparing lectures as well as presentations, about the progress of the project –
 MS-Office/Flip HTML
- Created an online manual online interactive software manual for PLASMA Robo Help/ HTML

Software Developer/Information Architect GPMT Ltd, London May 2009 – July 2012

For the online Bullion and Precious Metal Trading

company. My key Responsibilities were:

• Designed, managed and updated the company's bullion trading website using ASP.Net/SQL/JS/HTML/CSS

Software Developer and Programmer Sim. Eng. Ltd, Leatherhead May 2000 – July 2008

 Designed and programmed the company's desktop simulation software using VB6, VB Controls, ActiveX COM & DII, DAO & Windows API

Appendix 1
Breakdown of my flagship project, PLASMA, since year 2000 in VB6 and since 2012 in VB.Net

Project	Description	Maintainability	Cyclomatic	Depth of	Class	Lines of
- 1 1 5 Joseph - 2 5 5 5 1 7 1 5 1 5 1 5 1 5 1 5 1 5 1 5 1	Index	Complexity	Inheritance	Coupling	Code	
Mes.Plasma.Report	Creates a PDF report of the Plasma Items	72	111	7	102	380
Mes.Plasma.FileRW	Saves Plasma data and graph on disk	85	238	7	72	630
Mes.Plasma.Database	Records the Plasma Items in a database grid	67	299	1	29	1334
Mes.Plasma.Global	Provides generic procedures for the other modules	77	823	1	44	1604
Mes.Plasma.Charts	Shows simulation results as charts on the screen	73	840	13	261	3378
Mes.Plasma.Simulation	Performs graph tracing and finds out the results of					
Wes.r lasma.simulation	simulating what is on display on the screen	62	3070	10	123	10472
Mes.Plasma.MDI	Implements the MDI frame of the overall software	68	7222	12	939	25374
Mes.Plasma.Draw Supports the Graph drawing and the display of all the screen items of Plasma						
	68	12669	10	530	34138	
					Total:	77310

